<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code and Stuff</title>
    <link>https://ferdy89.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Code and Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>ferdy89@gmail.com (Fernando Seror)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ferdy89@gmail.com (Fernando Seror)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 20:53:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ferdy89.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating a Rails app from Heroku to a Raspbery Pi</title>
      <link>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/heroku-to-raspbery-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 20:53:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>ferdy89@gmail.com (Fernando Seror)</author>
      <guid>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/heroku-to-raspbery-pi/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve got a Rails app called MovieMates that I&#39;ve been building on my spare time for a few years now. When it got mature enough, I deployed it to Heroku for 3 reasons:
 Convenience (a basic deployment for Rails is as simple as git push heroku, and a lot of the tools out there are optimized for Heroku, including Rails itself) Free PostgreSQL database (which for a toy app like mine, means less money and peace of mind due to auto-management and free backups) Automatic TLS certificate management  However, there is one disadvantage:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My OOP Style</title>
      <link>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/my-oop-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 20:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>ferdy89@gmail.com (Fernando Seror)</author>
      <guid>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/my-oop-style/</guid>
      <description>I love Object Oriented Programming. This seems to be a somewhat controversial statement these days, but I love how good OO code can model reality and feel obvious to the human brain. To me, code that tells a good story might be one of the most valuable properties of a system.
I spend a lot of time trying to make my code tell a good story. I love to find a mental model that bridges human understanding with computer logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Sourcing Moviemates</title>
      <link>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/open-sourcing-moviemates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 08:51:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ferdy89@gmail.com (Fernando Seror)</author>
      <guid>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/open-sourcing-moviemates/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago I talked about this project I&#39;ve been working on for the past few years, MovieMates. Back in August, I made the service public for anybody to use and a few days ago I also open sourced its code. I wanted to talk a little bit more about why I did this and why did I do it now.
The reason why I did this won&#39;t come as a surprise for those who know me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MovieMates</title>
      <link>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/moviemates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 20:34:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>ferdy89@gmail.com (Fernando Seror)</author>
      <guid>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/moviemates/</guid>
      <description>This is the story of MovieMates, a service I built with my roommates to help us determine what movies to watch.
I share an apartment with 3 other people and we love watching movies. Living in a cold city like Chicago, it&#39;s one of our favorite hobbies during the long winters.
About 2 years ago, we noticed that many times it would take us very long to decide which movie to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unique Thread</title>
      <link>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/unique-thread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 18:37:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>ferdy89@gmail.com (Fernando Seror)</author>
      <guid>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/unique-thread/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote a new library for Ruby called Unique Thread. It allows multiple Ruby processes to communicate through Redis so only one of them is running a given thread concurrently. The idea for this came to me when wanting to run a crontab runner on a Rails app but only wanted one of the processes to be running at any given time. If the process running the thread shuts down, I also wanted another process to wake up and start running in its place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Code and Stuff</title>
      <link>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/introducing-code-and-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 19:29:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>ferdy89@gmail.com (Fernando Seror)</author>
      <guid>https://ferdy89.github.io/post/introducing-code-and-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
My name is Fernando and I code professionally. I have been into computers since I was very young and I&#39;ve devoted a big part of my life to it.
I currently work primarily with Ruby and one of the things I love the most about it is its community. I&#39;ve learned a lot from watching conference talks and reading on the Internet, and most of that content was created by people in their free time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>